What?
Rio is my cousin and a
prince of this kingdom?
Yes, that's how things turned out.
It isn't officially acknowledged,
but Rio is of the royal family.
Could it be that the two
of you are teasing me?
There's no way an average village
person could marry a princess!
Rio's father gained
recognition during the war,
and was raised to the rank of warrior-noble.
All of us elderly folk
in the village know the story.
A warrior-noble... In that case, it wouldn't
be so strange to meet a princess.
Would it?
That's what I've been saying, isn't it?
Huh? Uh... L-L-Lord Rio!
I-I apologize for my rudeness!
Please, wait. Let's not do that, all right?
B-But...
L-Lord Rio, you're royalty, aren't you?
My mother may have been,
but I'm not. So, please...
Treat me the way you have been up to now.
Rio... Can I call you that?
Of course.
Please, do everything the
way you have been doing it.
I will do that.
Your speech hasn't changed back.
Oh! Yes, uh, yeah.
This is all so sudden.
It must be troubling,
but Miss Ruri, I hope to
continue our relationship.
Yeah, all right.
Oh. That means...
Since we're cousins, calling
me "Miss" Ruri is a little...
I want you to refer to me
in a more familiar way.
Can't you?
Well, um... Yes, that's true.
No, sorry. You're right, Ruri.
Will this work all right?
Yeah!
And, this might be a little premature, but...
There is something I would
like to tell both of you.
You're being so formal. What is it?
I'm thinking of leaving this
village by this time next year.
I see. You will be missed,
but it can't be helped, can it?
Will you return to the land
where you grew up?
Yes. There's somewhere I'd like
to stop by along the way, too.
You'll come back to this village
again someday, won't you?
Well... If it's permitted,
I'd like to come back one day.
Of course it's allowed!
What are you talking about?
That's right. Come back any time.
You're a member of this village, you know?
Thank you very much.
I was wondering...
Since you said there was somewhere
you wanted to stop by,
does that mean there's someone
waiting for you there?
We aren't related by blood,
but there's someone who thinks
of me as an older brother...
Seirei Gensouki
Each of Their Decisions
Hello!
Huh? Rio, what is it?
Oh, Ruri.
I haven't said hello to
everyone since coming back,
so I thought I'd go around
and see everyone properly.
Oh, I see.
Huh? What is it?
That manner of speaking!
Sir Rio, your tone of voice...
Why are you speaking with
Miss Ruri that way like it's normal?
Huh?
Oh, this is...
What's the meaning of this, Ruri?
Well, um...
I mean, we're living in the same house.
I just asked him to stop using all
that formal language, that's all.
She asked—Miss Ruri
asked me a long time ago,
so I've tried to change
the way I speak, but...
Does it sound strange?
No!
It isn't strange.
I want that, too!
Sir Rio!
It's not fair!
Rio!
I planted the seedlings in my area
just the way you told me to!
Thank you!
Then, will you go and help the
others who haven't finished yet?
Will do!
Rio!
Ruri's so hardworking!
She'll make a good bride!
What?
I think so, too!
What are you talking about? Stop it!
Don't tease me like that.
Miss Sayo?
Shall I help you?
Huh? Oh! Sir Rio, I-I'm so sorry.
I wasn't paying attention.
Please make sure you remember everything.
I'd like you to supervise everyone
in the village in what I've taught.
After I've gone, too.
What?
Though it all depends on
whether it turns out well.
Sir Rio...
Are you leaving the village?
Yes.
I haven't told anyone else yet,
but this fall, around the time
the harvest festival ends,
that's when I'm thinking of going.
This fall... I see...
B-But...
if you're staying close, you could come back
to the village regularly, couldn't you?
I'm planning to travel across the country,
so I don't know if I'll be
able to come back regularly.
Oh, but...
It's still early,
but I wanted to tell you well
ahead of time, Miss Sayo.
Miss Sayo?
Is something wrong?
Oh! No. It's nothing.
I got something in my eye.
Oh, I see! It's because
I have dirt on my hands!
I'll use spirit arts to make some water.
Please, use it to wash.
Sayo!
What's wrong?
I got some dirt in my eye.
Sir Rio was helping me wash it away.
Oh, are you all right?
Yes.
I'm behind on my section,
so I'll go back to work.
Oh, I'll help you!
I'm back.
H-Hey... Sayo?
What's wrong? Did something happen?
Sorry, Big Brother. I'm fine.
It's nothing. I'll make dinner.
This is no time to be cooking, is it?
Who was it? Who made you cry?
Was it Rio?
N-No, it's not like...
Sir Rio didn't do anything wrong.
That dirtbag!
No! It's not like that!
Sir Rio said he'll be leaving the village.
That's why...
He's leaving the village?
It's not like that. It has
nothing to do with Sir Rio.
Huh?
B-Big Brother!
Wait!
Hey, Rio!
Rio, are you there?
What do you want with Rio?
Uh...
Oh, Rio.
I'm begging you!
Please, stay in the village!
What?
I-I know that what I'm saying is selfish.
But, please, don't say anything
and just stay in the village!
B-Big Brother!
What are you doing?
I'm so sorry for the trouble
my brother has caused you!
Come on, Big Brother!
You're bothering them! Come on...
Sayo... But you...
I'm really so very sorry.
My brother and I will talk
everything through properly.
All right. I won't ask you
what happened for now.
Are you all right with that, Rio?
Yes, that is fine, but...
Th-Thank you so much!
Come on. We're going, Big Brother.
Man, that bathwater was great!
Did something happen?
It was nothing.
Title and rank hold no meaning here!
If you have confidence in your skills,
come and challenge me!
Go for it, Big Boss Gouki!
Dola, you're up!
Don't ask the impossible!
There's no way I can beat him!
Go on!
To leave Sir Rio to one side and
simply amuse himself at this feast...
He'll be getting a severe scolding later.
Oh, no. I would rather he enjoy himself
without regard to status here.
Really? We'll do that, then.
All right! We're making kamutan this year!
Anyone who wants some, line up!
He did it!
I think we should go ahead and eat.
What about you, Komomo?
Yes! I'm looking forward to
the kamutan Sir Rio made!
Ah, that was quite enjoyable!
Mistress Kayoko.
Thank you so much for your help today.
It's nothing. Lady Yuba kindly invited
us to this harvest festival.
It was the least I could do in return.
We're honored and grateful.
E-Excuse me...
Sir Rio, may I have a moment?
Yes. What is it?
Um, I wanted to discuss something...
Father, you were amazing!
You think so?
I'll make it again sometime!
That hairpin...
You're still using it.
Oh... Yes.
I-I...
Um...
I know it may be burdensome
to hear this, but...
I-I...
I am in love with you, Sir Rio!
Miss Sayo, I'm sorry.
I can't return your feelings.
I-Is that because... Is it because
you're leaving the village, Sir Rio?
That isn't the whole reason, but... yes.
Then, please, take me with you!
Th-That's not possible!
I've worked hard so that
I wouldn't slow you down!
I've trained my body and practiced my
spirit arts every day for the last six months!
That's...
Please! I'll do anything!
I'll do everything I can
not to hold you back!
That isn't the issue at all.
I'm very sorry.
I cannot return your feelings.
That's all right.
Even if you never look at me...
Even if you never do anything for me...
It's all right.
Just let me...
At the very least...
Let me stay by your side.
I beg of you.
Miss Sayo.
I'm sorry.
I truly am.
Sir Rio...
Wait...
I'm sorry, Master Shin.
That creep. He noticed.
He really is a despicable one.
Blast it.
Thank you for everything
you've done for me.
Take care, both of you.
You don't need to set out
when it's still so dark.
I finished my goodbyes with
everyone in the village yesterday.
And it's going to be a long journey.
You can come back home anytime, all right?
Thank you.
So, in the end, she didn't come.
I'll be off, then.
Yes. Be sure to take care of yourself.
I will. Ruri, Mistress Yuba,
I hope you both stay well.
Rio!
Take care!
Have a good trip!
Miss Sayo?
Young lady.
Are you in love with Sir Rio?
What? Y-Yes.
Do you love him enough to cast aside
this village where you were born and raised?
W-Well, I...
Good.
I thought perhaps, but...
I seem to have misread things.
W-Wait, please!
I love him!
I love Sir Rio!
And there is no falsehood in your words?
There is not.
Then...
S-Sir Rio, um...
Please, take good care of yourself.
I will.
I hope you'll take even better
care of yourself, Miss Sayo.
I will. And...
Sir Rio!
What is it?
I'm going to work really hard!
I'll do my very best, so...
You have to do your best too, Sir Rio!
I will. I'll work very hard.
G-Good.
I am truly happy you came
to see me off, Miss Sayo.
Thank you very much.
I'm glad I gathered my
courage and came here, too.
Goodbye.
Yes. Until we meet again.
That's true. Until we meet again.
Year 999 of the Holy Era, Late Autumn
Is that...
Orphia's Ariel?
Onii-chan!
Welcome home!
I'm back.
I was able to have a lot of good experiences.
Well, that's the most important thing.
Onii-chan, you have a
grandmother and a cousin.
When I told them I have a little sister,
they both said they wanted to meet you.
I think I might want to meet them, too!
Well then, Sir Rio...
How long do you think you will be able
to stay in the village this time?
Probably a few months at most.
You're leaving again, Onii-chan?
I'm sorry, Latifa.
I'll make sure I come back
more quickly this time.
That's a promise, right?
Yes. That's a promise.
Sir Rio.
Was there anything you found yourself
running short of on your journey?
Oh, thank you.
I still have plenty in
the way of supplies,
but as I was traveling,
a thought did occur to me.
I was hoping that you might lend your wisdom.
Of course. Tell us.
Actually, I was thinking about building
a house I could take with
me in the space-time cache.
Oh, a house, huh?
That's an interesting thought!
Carrying a house... That would mean...
Would he want a house that could be
set in place without a foundation?
Yes.
But that said...
He'd probably have to use spirit arts
to prepare the ground every time.
Once he's like this,
he won't return for some time.
Indeed.
Sir Rio, leave the house to Dominic.
In the meantime, you should spend all the
time you can with Latifa and the others.
Right, Latifa?
Yeah!
I want to be with Onii-chan the
whole time he's in the village!
I've returned!
Welcome home!
Were you able to have a nice
long talk with the Eldest?
Yes. I was relieved to see that
everyone seems as sprightly as ever.
They all must have been surprised to see
how grown up you've gotten, Master Rio!
I suppose they were. It has
been two years, after all.
Master Rio, you've grown so much
that Miss Sara and Alma seem to
have gotten quite shy around you.
I-I'm not shy.
The only shy one here is Big Sister Sara.
A-Alma! Stop saying such weird things!
Why are you laughing, Master Rio?
No, it's just...
I just feel like I've really come home.
Both of you have become more like
grown ladies. You're lovely.
Th-Thank you.
I haven't changed much at all.
That's not true.
You've grown a little taller, haven't you?
Yes, well... just a little.
It must be so nice, Miss Sara, Alma,
to have Master Rio praise you like that.
Miss Orphia, you've become
more beautiful, too.
That calm aura of yours has only grown.
Thank you very much!
Say, Onii-chan!
Want to take a bath together?
What?
O-Of course he doesn't! What are you saying?
But why?
What's this?
So, I'm dreaming.
I'm still asleep. That's for certain.
Why am I...
sleeping with a naked girl?
Wh-What's the matter, Master Rio?
What's going on?
What is it?
What happened?
W-Wait! It's not like that!
It's a misunderstanding! This is—
What?!
Next Time
A Spirit's Awakening
"A Spirit's Awakening."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
Wh-Why is
there a naked
girl here?!
By Minazuki Futago
dazed
Am I still
half-asleep?
sleepy
mnn
I think
she's the
one who's
still
half-asleep.
food...
nom
nom...